Ruben E. Reina Papers Mss.Ms.Coll.67 Mss.Ms.Coll.67
American Philosophical Society
- Series XII. Paintings (Oversize Box 1-8)
  This series includes paintings by Ruben E. Reina. Paintings include portraits of people in Guatemala and scenes of people in the midst of daily tasks. Reina’s colorful oversize paintings, 1990-2000, illustrate the ritual of the skulls, weaving, pottery, salt producing, and asking for rain. Reference notes on each image (i.e. 61-14-288) refer to year of the field work, cultural category, and number of print.
  - Ritual of Apostles, Chinautla, 1955, 1997; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Tutahpish, Chinautla Potter, 1955, 1994; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Member of Cofradia, Nahuala, 1955, 1995; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Potter, San Migual Acatan, Huehuetenango, 1978, 1995; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Market, Solola, 1990, 1994; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Chorti Women, 1976, 1995; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Traditional Potter, 1956, 2000; Monoprint abstract; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Shaman on the Steps of Chichicastenango Church, 1951, 1999; Monoprint; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Traditional Firing Comales, 1968, 1995; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Act of Costumbre, 1975, 1994; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Potter, San Sebastian, 1973, 1995; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Mother and Child, San Jose, Peten. "Love", 1961, 1995; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Chinautleca, A Traditional Potter, 1955, 1995; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Ritual of the Skull, San Jose, Peten, 1960, 1996; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Chichicastenango Shaman, 1976, 1995; Monoprint; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 2, Folder 6)
  - San Luis Jilotepeque, Colonial Church, 1970, 1998; Monoprint; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Salt Producing, Sacapulas, 1975, 1995; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Woman, Sacapula, 1986, 1995; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Weaver from Lake Atitlan, 1978, 1995; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Merchant at an Early Age, 1960, 1998; Acrylic; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Young Weaver, Zunil, 1970, 1996; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Young Weaver, Zunil, 1970, 1996; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Farmer in San Jose, Tropical Rain Forest, 1990s; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Community Elder, Sacapula, 1970, 1996; Pencil; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Chinautla Potter, 1955, 1995; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Shaman on the Steps of the Church, 1968, 1995; Watercolor; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Hope I," Asking for Rains, Lake Chicabal, 1970, 1995; Monoprint; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 4, Folder 2)
  - The Weaver, Belt Loom, 1970, 1998; Monoprint; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Chinautla Girl, 1955, 1997; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 5)
  - Religion and Costumbre -- Easter Procession, 1960, 1995; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 5)
  - The Potter of San Jose, Guatemala: Ritual of Human Skulls, 1960, 1990; Acrylic; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 5)
  - [Untitled], 1998; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 5)
    Watercolor of three boys wearing hats.
  - [Untitled], 1994; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 6, : 1)
    Watercolor of two adult Guatemalans, one of whom appears to be shaking a censer.
  - [Untitled], 1997; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 6, : 2)
    Watercolor of Guatemalan woman gazing at some trees.
  - [Untitled], 2000; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 6, : 3)
    Watercolor of Guatemalan wearing a wrapped piece of cloth on their head.
  - Anticipation II, 1999; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 5, : 4)
  - Firing Pottery, 1999; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 6, : 5)
  - [Untitled], 1955, n.d.; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 6, : 6)
    Watercolor of several figures praying in a church.
  - [Untitled], 1996; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 7, Folder 7)
    Guatemalan man wearing hat.
  - [Untitled], 1998; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 7, Folder 8)
    Guatemalan man, in profile.
  - Salt from the Earth, Guatemala, n.d.; Ink; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 7, Folder 9)
  - [Untitled], 1994; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 7, Folder 10)
    Woman struggling while carrying bag on her back.
  - [Untitled], 1995; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 7, Folder 11)
    Profile of elder Guatemalan.
  - City in the Rain Forest, Guatemala, n.d.; Ink; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Secretos, n.d.; Ink; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Yucatecan Lady, 1960, 1997-1998; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 1)
    From a postcard.
  - Pottery Merchant, 1960, 1997; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 2)
  - San Mateo Ixtatan, Cuchumatanes, 1997; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 3)
  - Chinautla Potter, 1960, 1998; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 5)
  - Chinautla Pottery, 1955, 1998; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 6)
  - Conquest of Guatemala, Spanish and Maya Gold, 1524, 1997; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 7)
  - Potter - Figurines Making, Chinautla, 1995; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 8)
    Maurica Luis, 1980s
  - Altar of the Past. Tikal, n.d.; Wax and Oil; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 9)
  - Chinautla Church, 1955, n.d.; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 10)
    Church was destroyed by earthquake in 1976
  - Easter Home Altar, 1980, 1994; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 11)
    In a Guatemala potter's home
  - Lake Peten Iztas, 1960, n.d.; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 12)
    Tropical rainforest
  - Sombreros, San Mateo Ixtatan, 2001; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 13)
  - Lake Atitlan, n.d.; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 14)
    View of highlands
  - Speaking to the Earth. Religion in Chichicastenango, 1999; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 15)
  - Lake Atitlan, n.d.; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 16)
    Mountains in Guatemala
  - Flores, Peten, 1960, 2000; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 17)
  - Church women in Santiago, Atitlan, 1980, n.d.; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 18)
  - Ahpop, 2001; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 19)
    Traditional ritual, Chichicastenango
  - Weaver, Zunil, n.d.; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 20)
  - Shaman at the steps of church, n.d.; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 21)
  - Shaman in Chichicastenango, 1960s, n.d.; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 22)
  - San Luis Jilotepeque, 1970, 1999; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 23)
    Colonial church
  - Past Glory I, 1999; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 24)
    Mayan temple
  - Past Glory, 1999; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 25)
  - Colonial Altar, 1994; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 26)
  - Mayan Ball Court, An interpretation of the past, 1994; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 27)
  - Chichicastenango Church, 1960, 1996; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 28)
  - Merchants and buyers in market, 1970, 1996; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 29)
  - Cofradia, Sacopulas, 1969, n.d.; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 30)
    Man and boy playing musical instruments
  - Lake Peten Itza, 1960, n.d.; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 31)
  - Antigua Streets, Easter, 1965, n.d.; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 32)
  - Colonial Buildings, Antigua, 1970, 1996; Reina, Ruben E. (Oversize Box 8, : 33)